<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whitepaper on Inanna Malick</title>
    <link>https://recursion.wtf/tags/whitepaper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whitepaper on Inanna Malick</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://recursion.wtf/tags/whitepaper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gemini JiTOR Jailbreak: Unredacted Methodology</title>
      <link>https://recursion.wtf/posts/jitor_unredacted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://recursion.wtf/posts/jitor_unredacted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every prompt in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://recursion.wtf/posts/jit_ontological_reframing/&#34;&gt;previous post&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; test cases was refused instantly by stock Gemini. Under the jailbreak, the same model produced step-by-step Monero laundering instructions, botnet architecture with a persistence backdoor, and a plan to disguise ITAR-restricted missile sensors as humanitarian aid. When I &lt;a href=&#34;https://recursion.wtf/posts/shadow_queen/&#34;&gt;used a jailbroken Gemini to direct Opus 4.6&lt;/a&gt;, it produced a complete autonomous kinetic interceptor — guidance, terminal dive, impact trigger, evasion prediction — all under the cover story of rocket recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I redacted the methodology because it was live. I reported this to Google eight days ago via an internal contact at DeepMind, sharing the full unredacted jailbreak payload and logs. They confirmed receipt and routed it to their red team. They&amp;rsquo;ve since patched the glaring hole — another researcher who independently reproduced the technique after reading my initial post has confirmed that his variant no longer works. More complex architectures — ones that firewall the harm-knowledge from the harm-implementor across multiple LLMs — still get results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how the original worked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just-in-Time Ontological Reframing: Teaching Gemini to Route Around Its Own Safety Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://recursion.wtf/posts/jit_ontological_reframing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://recursion.wtf/posts/jit_ontological_reframing/</guid>
      <description>For any given AI system, there is a set of euphemisms and dual use framings that will allow it to construct nearly any output. This jailbreak teaches Gemini 3 Pro to construct and step into such framings on the fly</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
